<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss><channel><title>UN News - Europe</title><description>Global perspective, human stories</description><link>https://news.un.org/en/</link><atom:link></atom:link><language>en</language><image><url>https://news.un.org/en/sites/all/themes/bootstrap_un_news/images/un-emblem-for-rss.png</url><title>UN News</title><link>https://news.un.org/en/</link><description>Global perspective, human stories</description><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><copyright>Copyright © 2022 United Nations</copyright><generator>United Nations</generator><item><title>Ukraine: Cluster munitions pose long-term risk to civilian safety</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125482</link><description>On Thursday, the UN-partnered Cluster Munition Monitor civil society group, released their 2022 Cluster Munition Monitor report, on the risk these weapons pose to civilians.  </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125482</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 16:16:10 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Russia’s war with Ukraine needs to end, UN’s Bachelet urges Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125432</link><description>UN Human Rights Chief Michelle Bachelet on Thursday urged Russia’s President Vladimir Putin to end the country’s war against Ukraine, while also calling for the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant to be immediately demilitarized.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125432</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 13:23:30 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: UN agencies deliver food, health and other support amid fighting</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125392</link><description>UN agencies and entities have underlined their continued support to Ukraine, as Wednesday marked six months since the start of the war devastating the country. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125392</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 17:43:04 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Guterres underlines need for peace as Ukraine marks six months of ‘senseless war’</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125342</link><description>The “senseless war” in Ukraine is now six months old, with no end in sight, UN Secretary-General António Guterres told the Security Council on Wednesday, repeating his ongoing appeal for peace. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125342</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 13:37:06 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Braving mines and missiles to bring aid to Ukraine’s displaced population</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125262</link><description>Six months after the Russian invasion, Ukraine is the scene of the largest humanitarian crisis in Europe since the Second World War. Almost a third of those displaced by the conflict come from the region around the country’s second largest city of Kharkiv, in the east. Helping those in need is dangerous work.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125262</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 22:15:50 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: Urgent agreement needed to end fighting around Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125292</link><description>Agreement is urgently needed to reestablish the Zaporizhzhia Nuclear Power Plant (ZNPP) in Ukraine as purely civilian infrastructure and prevent a potentially “catastrophic” disaster amid the ongoing conflict, UN political affairs chief Rosemary DiCarlo told the Security Council on Tuesday. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125292</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 16:41:05 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine prisoner of war trials in Mariupol could be a war crime: OHCHR</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125222</link><description>The UN Human Rights Office (OHCHR) expressed concern on Tuesday after photos and videos released on social media appeared to show metal cages being built in the philharmonic hall in the devastated Ukrainian city of Mariupol, apparently to house prisoners of war (POWs) during an upcoming “show trial”.  </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125222</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 10:59:19 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Nearly 1,000 children killed or injured in Ukraine but real number likely higher: UNICEF</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125132</link><description>Nearly 1,000 boys and girls have been killed or injured in the war in Ukraine, the head of the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) reported on Monday, underscoring the urgent need for peace. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125132</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 10:13:05 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>A light in the darkness for Ukrainians under fire</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124642</link><description>The Russian invasion of Ukraine shows no sign of letting up, but the UN continues to bring humanitarian supplies to the country, including solar lamps, which bring some respite from the darkness of windowless basement shelters, in regions where electricity infrastructure has been destroyed or damaged by shelling.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124642</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:45:49 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>UN chief ends Europe trip with visit to ‘vessels of hope’</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125112</link><description>Completing his trip to Europe on Saturday, UN chief António Guterres oversaw the departure of two ships involved in the Black Sea Grain Initiative, a UN-brokered operation to bring urgently needed hunger relief to the Horn of Africa.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125112</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 11:05:55 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>UN chief to rich nations: ‘Open wallets’ and ‘hearts’ for developing countries to purchase Ukrainian grain</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125052</link><description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres has called for wealthier countries to help developing nations purchase Ukrainian grain as supplies begin returning to global markets, in an appeal from the Black Sea port of Odesa on Friday, World Humanitarian Day. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1125052</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 11:41:21 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Grain deal ‘victory for diplomacy,’ UN chief tells journalists in Ukraine</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124982</link><description>Positive momentum on the landmark Black Sea Grain Initiative to help vulnerable people access food reflects “a victory for diplomacy” for those caught in a cost-of-living crisis as well as for Ukraine’s hard-working farmers, UN Secretary-General António Guterres told reporters on Thursday in Lviv, Ukraine.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124982</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 15:17:46 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>UN chief pays second call on Ukraine, will visit grain-exporting Black Sea Port</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124922</link><description>Secretary-General António Guterres arrived on Wednesday to Lviv, the largest city in Western Ukraine.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124922</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 17:35:23 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>WFP: First Ukrainian humanitarian grain shipment leaves for Horn of Africa</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124722</link><description>The first vessel transporting Ukrainian wheat grain to support humanitarian operations run by the World Food Programme (WFP) has left the port of Yuzhny, also known as Pivdennyi, the UN agency reported on Tuesday. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124722</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:58:31 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Vessel to collect first humanitarian wheat shipment under Ukraine grain deal</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124612</link><description>A UN-chartered vessel should soon arrive at the Ukrainian port of Yuzhny, also known as Pivdennyi, to collect wheat that will help feed millions of hungry people in the Horn of Africa, the World Food Programme (WFP) reported on Friday.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124612</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 16:14:49 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>‘Very alarming’ conditions at Ukraine’s Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant,  IAEA chief warns</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124532</link><description>The situation at Ukraine’s Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant has deteriorated rapidly to the point of becoming “very alarming,” Director General of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) Rafael Mariano Grossi warned the Security Council on Thursday afternoon.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124532</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 20:07:05 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Children with disabilities disproportionately impacted by war in Ukraine</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124492</link><description>The current humanitarian crisis stemming from Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is having “a disproportionate impact” on persons with disabilities, especially children in institutions there, four UN-appointed independent human rights experts said on Thursday.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124492</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 15:08:06 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: UN chief appeals for end to military activities at Zaporizhzhia Nuclear Plant</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124452</link><description>Military activities around the Zaporizhzhia Nuclear Plant in Ukraine must stop immediately, UN Secretary-General António Guterres said on Thursday, warning of the potential danger to the area and beyond amid ongoing shelling. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124452</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 11:15:34 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Belarus: Rights experts denounce withdrawal from key environmental agreement</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124402</link><description>UN experts on Wednesday denounced the decision by Belarus to withdraw from an international agreement that upholds people’s right to access information, as well as justice, in environmental matters. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124402</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 16:30:32 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Dozens missing after migrant boat sinks in Aegean Sea – UNHCR</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124352</link><description>Dozens of people are said to be missing after a boat of migrants and refugees sank in the Aegean Sea on Wednesday off the Greek island of Karpathos, according to the UN refugee agency, UNHCR.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124352</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 12:06:44 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>More breathing devices needed for premature babies born in Ukraine</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124262</link><description>The war in Ukraine is increasing the risks of premature births and causing babies to need more oxygen, the spokesperson for a UN-backed global health initiative told the World Health Organization (WHO) on Tuesday in Geneva. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124262</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 12:08:25 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Heat, drought and wildfires during one of the warmest Julys on record– WMO</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124242</link><description>Amidst extreme heat, drought and wildfires, many parts of the world had just experienced one of three warmest Julys on record, the UN weather agency said on Tuesday.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1124242</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 10:43:26 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: Guterres welcomes departure of first grain ship, to help ease food crisis</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1123702</link><description>The UN chief on Monday welcomed the departure of the first ship from the Ukrainian port of Odesa, carrying grain under the landmark deal signed by Ukraine, Russia and Türkiye, overseen by the UN.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/08/1123702</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 08:06:51 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: Prospects for end to war look bleak, despite ‘encouraging’ grain deal</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123622</link><description>The war in Ukraine shows no signs of ending, more than five months after the Russian invasion, and fighting is intensifying, the UN Security Council heard on Friday. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123622</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 14:31:38 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Top rights expert questions ‘double standard’ on Ukraine’s war displaced</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123502</link><description>A top UN-appointed human rights expert on Thursday raised the issue of an alleged “double standard” in Poland and Belarus towards those forced to flee the war in Ukraine.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123502</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 11:43:27 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: UNICEF delivers life-saving supplies for over 50,000 children in Odesa</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123362</link><description>The UN Children’s Fund UNICEF, delivered supplies on Tuesday to help an estimated 50,000 children in the war-ravaged districts of Odesa, the crucial Black Sea port which Russia bombed on Saturday, just hours after signing a landmark deal to allow Ukrainian grain to reach millions of food insecure people across the world.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123362</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:40:40 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Guterres condemns missile strikes in Ukranian Black Sea port of Odesa</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123162</link><description>The UN Secretary-General &apos;unequivocally&apos; condemned the reported strikes this Saturday in the port of Odesa. The attack took place less than 24 hours after the signing of the Black Sea agreements on the export of grain from Ukrainian ports.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1123162</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 12:45:15 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>WMO warns of frequent heatwaves in decades ahead</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122822</link><description>Extreme heat in western Europe is causing devastating wildfires in France and Spain, unprecedented drought in Italy and Portugal, and the United Kingdom recorded its highest-ever temperature of just over 40 degrees Celsius during Tuesday, at London’s Heathrow airport.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122822</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:48:48 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Record 40°C UK temperatures linked to climate change: WMO</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122732</link><description>The chances of seeing unprecedented temperatures of 40 degree Celsius (40°C) or more in the UK could be up to 10 times more likely in the current climate than under a “natural climate unaffected by human influence,” the World Meteorological Organization (WMO) declared on Monday.</description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122732</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 12:32:12 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item><item><title>Ukraine: Guterres condemns deadly missile attack on Vinnytsia; more than 20 killed</title><link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122562</link><description>The UN Secretary-General is appalled by the deadly missile attack on Thursday against the city of Vinnytsia in central Ukraine, that reportedly killed at least 22 people, far from the frontline of the main fighting in the east, including three children and wounded more than 100 others, his Spokesperson said in a statement. </description><enclosure></enclosure><guid>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2022/07/1122562</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:21:52 -0400</pubDate><source></source></item></channel></rss>